Andrew K. Saydjari

EMAIL: saydjari@g.harvard.edu phone: 715-530-1634 orcid: D 0000-0002-6561-9002

OBJECTIVE

To work at the interface of data science and astrophysics in pursuit of a Ph.D. and career in academic research. Research interests include wavelet transforms, nongaussianity, turbulence in the interstellar medium, and stellar feedback. My ideal day is playing with data and discovering hidden knowledge within. My experimental background affords unique insight into data acquisition which further informs my data analysis skills.

EDUCATION

2018 – 2024 Harvard University

PhD Physics Finkbeiner Group

GPA: 4.0

2014 – 2018 Yale University

BS/MS Chemistry & BS Mathematics 7(8) Physics (Chemistry) Grad Courses

GPA: 3.93

2000 – 2014 Lincoln High School, WI

13 Advanced Placement Courses (5/5)

2 Univ. Wisconsin Courses

GPA: 4.00

AWARDS

National

2019 Hertz Finalist

2018 NSFGRFP Fellow

2018 Hertz Finalist

2017 Barry Goldwater Scholar

University

2018 Howard Douglass Moore Prize

2017 Rosenfeld Science Scholar

2016 DAAD/Tetelman/Bergin

Honor Societies

2017 Phi Beta Kappa

2017 Sigma Xi

2017 Alpha Epsilon Mu

STANDARDIZED EXAMS

GRE 880 Chemistry (94%), 870 Physics (81%) 170 Quant (99%), 170 Verbal (97%) 5 Writing (93%)

OUTREACH

Harvard Observation Project

Aug 2020 – Present Advisor

Running observation and data analysis sessions on the Clay telescope at Harvard for undergraduates. Jointly advised an extension school student on improving an FFT-based deconvolution algorithm ("Online Blind Deconvolution") in PYTHON for short exposure imaging. Goal is to improve resolution of nearby binary stars and signal-to-noise for planetary transits.

LitKit: Educational Fluorescence Microscopy Kit DEC 2017 – Jun 2019 Non-Profit Co-Founder

Developing a safe, cost-effective educational kit to transform a standard secondary school microscope into a fluorescent microscope. This technology allows live cell imaging, bringing dynamic cellular processes to life before nascent scientists. Lead designer of laser optics and mount to utilize an ordinary laser pointer for excitation.

PUBLICATIONS

GRADUATE

Saydjari, A. K.; Portillo, S.K.N.; Slepian, Z.; Kahraman, S.; Burkhart, B.; Finkbeiner, D.; Classification of Magnetohydrodynamic Simulations using Wavelet Scattering Transforms.

Portillo, S.K.N.; Slepian, Z.; Kahraman, S.; **Saydjari, A. K.**; Burkhart, B.; Finkbeiner, D.;

Accelerated 3PCF with FFTs.

arXiv:2010.11963. 2020.

in prep. 2020.

Alegria, L.D.; Bøttcher, C.G.; **Saydjari, A. K.**; Pierce, A.T.; Lee, S.H.; Harvey, S.P.; Vool, U.; Yacoby, A.; High-Energy Quasiparticle Injection in Mesoscopic Superconductors.

arXiv:2005.00584. 2020.

Undergrad

Charboneau, D.J.; Brudvig, G.W.; Hazari, N.; Lant,

H.M.C.; Saydjari, A. K.;

Development of an Improved System for the Carboxylation of Aryl Halides through Mechanistic Studies.

ACS Catal. 2019, 9, 3228-3241.

McKee, A.; Solano, M.; **Saydjari, A. K.**; Bennett, C.J.; Hud, N.V.; Orlando, T.M.;

A Possible Path to Prebiotic Peptides Involving Silica and Hydroxy Acid-Mediated Amide Bond Formation. *ChemBioChem.* **2018**, *19*, 1-6. [VERY IMPORT. PAPER]

Wang, D.; Wagner, M.; **Saydjari, A.**; Wu, S.; Butt, H.; A Photoresponsive Orthogonal Supramolecular Complex Based on Host–Guest Interactions.

Chem. Eur. J. 2017, 23, 2628-2634.

Saydjari, A. K.; Weis, P.; Wu, S.;

Spanning the Solar Spectrum: Azopolymer Solar Thermal Fuels for Simultaneous UV and Visible Light Storage. *Adv. Energy Mat.* **2016**, 7, 1601622. [COVER ARTICLE]

HIGH SCHOOL

Saydjari, A. K.; Pietron, J. J.; Simpkins, B. S.; Electrochemical Deposition and Spectroelectro-chemical Response of Bromophenol Blue Films on Gold. *Electroanalysis*. **2015**, *27*, 1960-1967.

Saydjari, A. K.; Long, J.; Dressick, W.; Simpkins, B.; Optical Interference Effect Corrections for Absorbance Spectra of Layer-by-Layer Thin Films Bearing Covalently Bound Dye.

Chem. Phys. Lett. 2014, 608, 328-333.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Harvard Physics Department

Prof. Douglas Finkbeiner

Aug 2020 – Present Graduate

Designing and characterizing new statistics based on wavelets to capture non-gaussianity in the interstellar medium. Pushing to make these statistics robust enough to apply to observations in addition to simulations, helping to bridge the gap between theory and observation. These statistics will then be applied to infer the Mach numbers of observed dust clouds.

Prof. Amir Yacoby

July 2018 - Aug 2020

GRADUATE

Engineering and investigating topological states of matter. Key questions include unambiguous detection, quantifying "topological protection," and decoherence mechanisms. Experimental focus on Josephson phenomenon using InAs and HgTe quantum wells. Repaired dilution refrigerator. Simulated, fabricated, and characterized first zig-zag Josephson junctions.

Yale Physics Department

Prof. Michel Devoret

Jan 2018 – Jun 2018

Undergrad

Designing, fabricating, and measuring novel 3D Josephson junction geometries. *In situ* fabrication of a completely enclosed junction to improve junction coherence times, reproducibility, and processibility.

Yale Chemistry Department

Prof. Nilay Hazari

Aug 2016 - May 2018

Undergrad

Performing mechanistic studies on nickel catalyzed carboxylation of aryl halides using carbon dioxide. Designing low-valent metal traps for study of kinetics of precatalyst activation. Mechanistic studies will then be used to direct the development of highly efficient catalysts.

Prof. Charles Schmuttenmaer

SEP 2015 - MAY 2016

Undergrad

Rebuilt terahertz spectrometer from scratch in pursuit of the first circular dichroism spectrum using terahertz-time domain spectroscopy.

Max Planck Institute for Polymer Research

Dr. Hans-Jürgen Butt

May 2016 - Aug 2016

Undergrad

Designed and created an azopolymer-based solar thermal cell with record-breaking efficiency and gravimetric energy density. Calculated host-guest molecule geometries elucidating mechanism behind novel assemblies which lead to first photo-responsive orthogonal supramolecular systems.

Georgia Institute for Technology

Prof. Nicholas V. Hud

May 2015 - Jul 2015

Undergrad

Reached record polypeptide lengths under prebiotically plausible conditions by examining a novel system which simultaneously explored the role of surfaces and mixtures on Early Earth. Elucidated the mechanism for observed unprecedented protection (with applications to food science). This work provided confirmation of plausibility of the peptide world hypothesis.

U.S. Naval Research Lab

Dr. Blake Simpkins

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

High School

Achieved first direct electrochemical deposition of bromophenol blue on gold. Characterized film growth with respect to deposition variables and demonstrated electrochemical control of film optical states.

Jun 2013 - Aug 2013

HIGH SCHOOL

Fabricated and analyzed polyelectrolyte multilayer films using spectroscopy and microscopy. Analyzed spectra and developed a mathematical model for spectral correction.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2015 – 2018 Yale University Peer Tutor

Physical Chemistry Lab/Lecture Organic Chemistry (Fresh/Soph)

 $2015-2018 \quad \textbf{SPLASH/SPROUT@Yale}$

Middle/High School Courses

Course List

Peeling Back the Layers of Solar Cells

Class size: 30

Metal Mania: Simple Models of the Material World

Class size: 4
Destressing Tensors
Class size: 7

Abstract Algebra: Questions Teachers Didn't Answer

Class size: 60, 75

Origins of Life: A Chemist's Perspective

Class size: 16, 35

Conferences

Speaker

2020 APS: March Meeting

Boulder, CO
APS: March

2019 APS: March Meeting Boston, MA

Best Presentation

2017 Gulf Coast Research Conference Rice University

2017 Ivy League STAR Competition Award of Excellence

2017 Yale Research Symposium Plenary

2016 National Collegiate Research Conference Harvard

Spectroscopy Poster Presenter 2019 Center for Integrated Quantum Materials Terahertz-Time Domain SPR (Surface Plasmon Resonance) 2016 Yale Research Showcase XPS (X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy) 2016 Columbia Science Symposium NMR (1H, 13C, 31P, 1H-1H NOSEY)/EPR Award of Excellence UV-vis-NIR/Fluorescence 2015 Yale Research Symposium Reflectance/Diffuse/ATR-FTIR Grand Prize Misc 2015 GeorgiaTech Poster Session Dynamic Light Scattering/Zeta Potential (Polarized) Optical Microscopy (Super Res) 2014 NRL Science Apprenticeship Conference Confocal Microscopy/Optical Trapping EDITING Optical Contact Angle Measurement 2017 Journal of Epsilon Alpha Mu Society DSC (Differential Scanning Calorimetry) Technical Editor Elemental Analysis Max Planck Institute for Polymers 2016-2020 Computational Skills Language Editor **Programming**

Laboratory Skills

Characterization

(S)TEM/EDX (Transmission Electron Microscopy)

FIB (Focused Ion Beam)

SEM-EDS (Scanning Electron Microscopy) AFM (Atomic Force Microscopy)/Profilometry

Fabrication

Electron Beam Lithography

Reactive Ion Etching

Thermal/Electron Beam Metal Deposition

Atomic Layer Deposition

Electrochemistry

CV (Cyclic Voltammetry) Electrochemical Deposition In situ-Spectroelectrochemistry

DNA Science

Gel Electrophoresis

PCR (Polymerase Chain Reaction)

Analytical

(U)HPLC-MS/MS

GC/MEMS (Chemicapacitor)

GPC-SES/FID

Python Spark

SQL

LABVIEW

Numerical Packages

Kwant

QuantumEspresso Gaussian09/16 **GAMESSUS**

Data Suites

MATLAB Mathematica **IgorPro** Origin

Formatting Software

LALEX

AutoCAD/Inventor/Maya Chemissan/Avogadro

LANGAUGES

English (Native), French (6 yrs)